Minh Mai, Data Scientist.

Profile

Data Scientist with experience in munging data, building statistical models, visualizing and mapping data, and managing projects to ensure error-free deliverables. Good sense of humor.

Skills

Data Analysis: R, Python (pandas, numpy, scikit-learn), SPSS, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, SPSS, Stata

Visualization: QGIS, JavaScript (D3, dc.js, Mapbox/Leaflet.js), HTML/CSS, Tableau

Other programs: git, Linux/UNIX scripting, and advanced Excel (VBA macros/PowerPivot)

Languages: Vietnamese (native) and Spanish (basic proficiency)

Experience

Optimus Consulting, Data Scientist

Aug 2013 - Present

- Oversaw segment monitoring and political polling that contacted over 200,000 voters weekly throughout 12 states simultaneously
- Utilize machine learning and statistical models to micro-target and segment voters in over twenty states
- Analyze numerous randomized field tests that optimized and directed millions of dollars in campaign expenditures
- Manage reporting processes from building client-facing products to internal reports on how to execute actionable tasks from analytics for our clients
- Train a small cohort of interns every summer to produce error-free deliverables

National Center for Policy Analysis, Development Associate

May 2012 - May 2013

- Analyzed trends to create a portfolio of 40 corporate donors that culminated in thousands of dollars raised
- Assisted in building and branding a new healthcare advocacy group that launched policy initiatives to improve the Affordable Care Act

Relevant Projects

Clark University, Master's Thesis

August 2011 – May 2012

- Collaborated with staff on university's fundraising department to analyze data to improve young alumni participation rates
- Directed the entire data lifecycle of the project from survey design, collection, cleaning, analysis using Stata, and presentation to stakeholders

ACE, Graduate Consultant

Jan 2012 – May 2012

Led a team to create a strategic marketing plan to resolve a \$150,000 funding gap in afterschool programming for African immigrants

Seven Hills Foundation, Graduate Consultant

Sept 2011 – Dec 2011

Designed and implemented a strategic management plan to maximize ROI on an acquisition valued at \$3 million

Education

Masters of Public Administration, GPA: 3.7 Bachelors of the Arts cum laude, Philosophy

2012

2011

Clark University